http://www.premiumbeat.com/privacy-policy

Our Privacy Policy
This Privacy Statement describes how Shutterstock Canada, ULC d/b/a Premiumbeat, and the Shutterstock group of companies
manage personal information and respect your privacy. This policy may be amended from time to time. We encourage visitors
to and users of our sites to regularly review our Privacy Policy.
All
“Personal Information” (which is defined as any information that identifies or can be used to identify, contact, or
locate the person to whom such information pertains) that we collect and maintain will be subject to this Privacy Policy,
as amended from time to time. To update your information and preferences, see the section entitled “Updating Your Personal Information and Privacy Preferences.”
When we refer to
“Shutterstock”, we mean the Shutterstock entity that acts as the controller or processor of your information, as explained
in more detail in the “Entities Collecting Personal Information” section below.
Entities Collecting Personal Information
Shutterstock is made up of different legal entities. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of the Shutterstock group of
companies so when we mention “Shutterstock”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant
company in the Shutterstock Group responsible for processing your data. The applicable Terms of Service or License Agreement
you enter into with Shutterstock will govern which Shutterstock company is the controller of your data. Personal Information
on this website is collected by Shutterstock Canada, ULC ULC, 4398, Boul. Saint-Laurent, Suite 103, Montreal, Quebec H2W
1Z5, Canada
We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) for the Shutterstock Group who is responsible for overseeing questions
in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions, concerns, or requests about this privacy notice, how we
manage your Personal Information, or any other issue relating to your Personal Information, please contact our DPO:
Shutterstock
Attn: Data Protection Officer
privacy@shutterstock.com
https://www.shutterstock.com/contactus
Controller (Location of Incorporation or Organization)
Properties
Shutterstock, Inc. (US)
www.shutterstock.com
www.offset.com
www.bigstockphoto.com
Rex Features Ltd. (UK)
www.rexfeatures.com
Shutterstock Canada, ULC ULC (Canada)
www.premiumbeat.com
www.rocketstock.com
Shutterstock Custom Platform ULC (Canada)
custom.shutterstock.com
Collection Of Personal Information
As a visitor to the Site, you can engage in many activities without providing any Personal Information.
However, when you register to use a Shutterstock site and order products or services as a Shutterstock subscriber in order
to provide the services to you, we may collect the following Personal Information from you:
Contact information such as your name, phone and fax numbers, address and email address; and
Billing information such as the number, expiration date, card type and billing address of your credit card;
Demographic information such as your job title, job description and company name and company type; and
Profile data, including your username and password, details about your purchases and the Content that you license from us.
If you submit content to Shutterstock for licensing, you may be asked to provide the following information:
Contact information such as your name, phone number, primary address, and email address.
Shutterstock may verify this information by asking you to either: a) upload a scan of a government issued ID (which will
be stored securely on our servers); or b) provide a credit card number. Your credit card number will be used solely for
the purpose of verifying your name and address. The credit card number will not be stored.
Payment and contributor information including, but not limited to, payout method, payout email, desired display name, content
focus, and information about your skill level process.
Depending upon the activity, some of the information that we ask you to provide is identified as mandatory and some as voluntary.
If you do not provide the mandatory data with respect to a particular activity, you will not be able to engage in that
activity.
As is true of most websites, when you use the Site, Shutterstock or third party subprocessors contracted by Shutterstock
may also collect certain technical and routing information about your computer to facilitate your use of the Site and its
services. For example, we may log environmental variables, such as browser type, operating system, CPU speed, and the Internet
Protocol (IP) address of your computer. We use these environmental variables to facilitate and track your use of the Site
and its services. Shutterstock also uses such environmental variables to measure traffic patterns on the Site. To better
understand the needs of our visitors to the Site we may occasionally match such information with your Personal Information.
In order to reduce errors in our database, authenticate our users, and prevent abuse of our system, we may on occasion supplement
the Personal Information you submit to us with information from third-party sources. For example, we may supplement your
contact information with address information provided by the U.S. Postal Service to qualify your information and prevent
errors in our database. We may supplement the information that we collect directly from you with information stored in
third-party databases, such as demographic information or company information in order to make it more likely that any
marketing communications we send will be relevant and of interest to you. You may find a list of any third-party subprocessors
that we use to process information here.
When you download and use our Mobile Apps or Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use,
and operating system version. We do not ask for, access or track any location-based information from your mobile device
at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or Services.
Updating Your Personal Information And Privacy Preferences
Upon request Shutterstock will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party,
any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at privacy@shutterstock.com.
You have the right to access and correct, or delete your Personal Information and privacy preferences at any time. You may
do so by contacting privacy@shutterstock.com.
How Your Personal Information Is Used
Shutterstock collects your information in order to provide services to you, comply with our legal obligations, and to improve
our products and services. We do not sell, rent or share your personally identifiable information to or with third parties
in any way other than as disclosed in this Privacy Policy. Shutterstock may use this information to:
Process your financial transactions.
Send you order / renewal confirmations.
Register your rights, if any, to technical support or other benefits that may be made available to registered users.
Respond to customer service requests, questions and concerns.
Administer your account.
Send you requested product or service information.
Keep you informed about special offers and services of Shutterstock and selected third parties.
Administer promotions and sweepstakes you enter and notify you of the results.
Investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities and/or violations of our Terms of Service.
Meet our research and product/service development needs and to improve our Site, services and offerings; and
Customize your experience, including targeting our services and offerings to you.
We store information that we collect through cookies, log files, transparent images, and/or third party sources to create
a summary of your preferences. We tie your personally identifiable information, and/or your membership usage history, to
information in the summary, in order to provide tailored promotions and marketing offers, to improve the content of the
site for you and/or to determine your preferences.
In certain situations, Shutterstock may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities,
including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
Where required by law (e.g., to comply with a subpoena, warrant, court order, or legal process served on Shutterstock), and
when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, avoid litigation, protect your safety or the safety
of others, investigate fraud, and/or respond to a government request. We may also disclose information about you if we
determine that such disclosure should be made for reasons of national security, law enforcement, or other issues of public
importance.
Information Sharing With Service Providers / Agents
Shutterstock uses one or more outside credit card processing companies to bill you for our goods and services. To the best
of our knowledge, these companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other
purpose.
We also share Personal Information with certain companies that perform services on our behalf. We only share the Personal
Information which is necessary for them to perform those services. We require any company with which we may share Personal
Information to protect that data in a manner consistent with this policy and to limit the use of such Personal Information
to the performance of services for Shutterstock. You may find a list of these third-party subprocessors here.
We do not sell or otherwise provide Personal Information to other companies for the marketing of their own products or services.
Data Retention
We will retain your information for as long as your account is active, your informationis needed to provide you services,
or as required to fulfill our legal obligations. If you wish to delete your account or request that we no longer use your
information to provide you services contact us at privacy@shutterstock.com. We will respond to your request within 30 days. We will retain and use your information as
necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.
Choice / Opt Out
You may “opt out” of receiving Shutterstock’s email updates, newsletters and/or partner emails by emailing privacy@shutterstock.com.
The choice to opt out of such communications is also generally available during the sign-up
process. Shutterstock will still contact you when there are changes to the Terms of Service or Submitter Terms of Service,
as applicable. In addition, we will still send you service-related announcements including, but not limited to, a registration
email, benefit notification emails, emails automatically triggered by actions you took on the Site and bill related notices.
Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you wish not to receive
them, you have the option of deactivating your account.
If you use a Shutterstock mobile app, we may send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any
events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn
them off at the device level.
Protection Of Your Personal Information
The Personal Information that you provide in connection with the use of the Site is protected in several ways.
Access by you to your account profile is available through a password and unique customer ID selected by you. This password
is encrypted. You should strive to use a strong, alpha-numeric password which you should not divulge to anyone.
Your Personal Information resides on secure servers that only selected Shutterstock personnel and contractors have access
to via password.
Your Personal Information is encrypted whenever it is transmitted to Shutterstock.
When you enter sensitive information (such as credit card number) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information
using transport layer security technology.
We strive to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However,
no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. While we take into account
the sensitivity of the Personal Information we collect, process and store, and the current state of technology to use these
measures protect your Personal Information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.
If you have any questions about security on our Web Sites, you can send email to us at privacy@shutterstock.com.
Cookie And Tracking Technologies
The Site may automatically collect information as you browse, such as Internet Service Provider, browser type and version,
operating system and device type, average time spent on our site(s), pages viewed, information accessed, the Internet Protocol
(IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet and other relevant statistics. Such information is sometimes
referred to as web analytics and/or clickstream data.
We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve
services we offer you, to improve marketing, analytics, and provide site functionality.
Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by Shutterstock and our affiliates, analytics services
and service to provide site features and functionality. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering
the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.
We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated
basis.
A cookie is a small, unique text file that a website can send to your computer when you visit a site. We may use session
cookies, which terminate when a user closes his or her browser, and/or persistent cookies, which remain on the user’s computer
until manually deleted. Most web browsers can either alert you to the use of cookies or refuse to accept cookies entirely.
If you do not want us to deploy cookies to your browser, you can set your browser to reject cookies or to notify you when
a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. Rejecting cookies may affect your ability to use the Site.
We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites.
Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and
other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have
this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking here (or if located
in the European Union click here) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive
generic ads.
We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone.
This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application,
aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store
within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.
Transfers Outside The Eea
Where we use certain service providers or share information within the Shutterstock Group, we may use specific contracts
approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. Where we use providers
based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the EU-US Privacy Shield which requires them to provide
similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US.
Changes In Privacy Policy
Shutterstock reserves the right to amend the Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion and will provide notice
by email or on the home page of the Site when we make material changes to this Privacy Policy prior to the change becoming
effective. If as the result of such changes, you want to alter the ways in which Shutterstock is allowed to use your Personal
Information, you can do so by following the procedure described in the section entitled “Updating Your Personal Information and Privacy Preferences.”
You will be deemed to have been made aware of, and will be subject to, any material changes to the Privacy Policy after such
notice has been posted with the following exception: If at the time you provide Personal Information to Shutterstock you
are given the opportunity (as you currently are) to limit how such information will be used to communicate with you, either
by Shutterstock or by third parties, Shutterstock will not change your preference in this regard without your express consent.
However, if Shutterstock is acquired by or merged with another entity, Shutterstock may provide to such entity customer
information that is related to that part of our business that was sold to or merged with the other entity without your
consent, but Shutterstock will provide notice of such asset sales, acquisitions, or mergers on this Site.
Links To Third Party Sites
Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Shutterstock. If you submit personal
information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully
read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.
Social Media Widgets
Our Web sites may include Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as the Share this button
or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting
on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either
hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy
policy of the company providing it.
Single Sign-On
You may be able to log in to our site using sign-in services such as Facebook Connect or an Open ID provider. These services
will authenticate your identity and provide you the option to share certain personal information with us such as your name
and email address to pre-populate our sign up form. Services like Facebook Connect give you the option to post information
about your activities on this Web site to your profile page to share with others within your network.
Referral Program Emails
If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our Site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email
address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Site. Shutterstock stores
this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.
Your friend may contact privacy@shutterstock.com to request that we remove this information from our database.
Children
We do not intend to solicit or collect Personal Information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are under 18, do not
enter information on this site or engage our services. If you believe a child of yours under the age of 18 has entered
Personal Information please contact support@premiumbeat.com to have the data removed and terminate the child’s account.
Privacy Complaints
Individuals located in certain countries, including the European Economic Area, have certain statutory rights in relation
to their personal data. Subject to any exemptions provided by law, you may have the right to request access to Information,
as well as to seek to update, delete or correct this Information.
To the extent that Shutterstock’s processing of your Personal Data is subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation,
Shutterstock relies on its legitimate interests, described above, to process your data. If you have any questions or concerns,
you may contact us by emailing privacy@shutterstock.com.
Shutterstock takes its users’ privacy concerns seriously. If you believe that Shutterstock has not complied with this Privacy
Policy with respect to your Personal Information, you may contact the Data Protection Officer at Shutterstock, Empire State
Building, 350 Fifth Avenue, 21st Floor, New York, NY 10118, USA. In your letter please describe in as much detail as possible
the ways in which you believe that the Shutterstock Privacy Policy has not been complied with. We will investigate your
complaint promptly.
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you
can contact our Data Protection Officer at privacy@shutterstock.com.
Shutterstock
Attn: Data Protection Officer
privacy@shutterstock.com
Shutterstock Canada, ULC ULC
4398, Boul. Saint-Laurent, Suite 103
Montreal, Quebec H2W 1Z5
Canada
Last updated on May 14th, 2018.Still Need Help?Send Us a Note!Through our simple music licensing and commitment to world-class support, we aim to provide you with the best possible customer experience.
If we can do anything to assist, please don’t hesitate to contact us.contact us
